#### Contact

satyadileep@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/k-v-s-dileep (LinkedIn) kvsdileep.me (Personal)

## Top Skills

Machine Learning LaTeX Matlab

### Honors-Awards

B.Sc Gold medal

1st prize at Yahoo! HackU Campus event

3rd prize at Yahoo! HackU event

### **Publications**

Estimating Case Base Complexity using Fractal dimension, KVS Dileep and Sutanu Chakraborti

Learning Data Dependent Composite Kernels for Robust Image Retrieval - A Genetic Programming Approach

Towards Higher Order Complexity Measures for Text Classification, KVS Dileep and Sutanu Chakraborti

Complexity guided noise filtering in QA Repositories, KVS Dileep, Swapnil Hingmire and Sutanu Chakraborti

Eager to be lazy: Towards a Complexity-guided Textual Case-Based Reasoning System, KVS Dileep and Sutanu Chakraborti

# K V S Dileep

Al Strategist and Startup Leader | Principles and frameworks to succeed in early-stage startups | Al-First Thinker

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

## Summary

7+ years of leadership experience in edtech and >12+ years of experience in education.

I am a T-shaped executive - with specialized skills in program management and 0-1 execution. I have good working knowledge of business strategy, data analytics, growth and all things startups. (Scroll down to see what I am learning).

I can zoom out and think strategically as well as zoom in and execute with my teammates in the trenches. I haven't been afraid to get my hands dirty and went beyond my job description - I did sales pitches, taught learners (data science), and handled learner escalations. I become the one the organization needs.

Empathy over sympathy is my management style. I listen more and guide the team to the solution instead of directly telling them. I am pessimistic in the short term and optimistic in the long term.

A word that guides my philosophy in life and work.

Kokoro | [n] | The intersection of heart, mind, & spirit that's a person's essence, soul, or centre. Instead of being treated separately, they are one.

## Experience

GrowthSchool 3 years 4 months

Head - User Engagement & Al Initiatives December 2023 - Present (1 year 7 months)

- Mapping customer lifecycle journeys and helping in effective rechurn of customers to recover revenue. Executed multiple 0-1 projects to improve revenue and customer retention.
- Executed multiple 0-1 projects to improve revenue and customer retention.

#### Head of Programs

March 2022 - December 2023 (1 year 10 months)

- Led the team to launch 20+ workshops and 10+ intensive programs to 2x revenue year-on-year. Worked cross-functionally with multiple teams and helped with data analysis for better lead scoring and improved revenue.

### Relevel by Unacademy

10 months

Sr. Manager, Learning Experience November 2021 - February 2022 (4 months)

- Was transferred to a new business unit Courses which was a small unit of ~4 people and helped grow it to ~50 people to deliver a stellar learning experience. Helped achieve an NPS > 80 in 60 days.
- Built the Learning Operations unit from scratch especially in setting up the learner experience loops and the way the Teaching Assistants interacted and added value to the learners.
- Set up the processes to execute the testing component of courses smoothly and helped scale it from few tests to now parallel tests across cohorts.
- Understood the operational gaps which needed product intervention and fleshed out the key problem statement and requirements.
- Created Standard Operating Procedures for all key activities of Learning Operations to get ready for scale.

# Sr. Manager, Test Design May 2021 - November 2021 (7 months)

- Owned the conception of Test Design and execution for the Tech categories
- Backend and Frontend for Relevel. Helped to launch the tests ~1.5 months with percentage of promoters out of 1000+ learners at 80%.
- Refined the various evaluation rubrics for tests and built a steady pipeline to enable the company to do daily tests from Oct 2021 onwards. Executed complex tasks with a very lean team.
- Understood the test taker pain points and gave inputs to the product team to help in picking the right features that will provide delight to the test takers.

- Analyzed the previous test takers' performance data across various competencies and rounds and helping the product validate crucial decisions regarding scoring mechanisms and qualification.
- Helped in the launch of tests of Data Analytics and Business Analytics and helped define the formats of cases studies for both these rounds.
- Trained ~100+ evaluators across the categories for fair evaluation of the candidates.

GreyAtom Head of Programs July 2018 - April 2021 (2 years 10 months) Mumbai Area, India

- Involved with the end-to-end lifecycle of our education products right from conception, persona mapping, design, GTM strategy and delivery.
- Continuously analyzed learner feedback and prepared the user stories for learner, mentor as well as admin from the learning point of view for effective engagement. Worked closed with the design team and gave feedback on design mockups and clarified blockers for the engg team to build out the features.
- Conceptualized, designed and delivered cohort-based courses on Data Science, Deep Learning and Frontend Web Development. For learners looking for a job change, we had placement ratio ~88%.
- During the pandemic crisis, I helped evolve a new course delivery model that helped us offer programs at a lower cost and keep the revenue flowing. (From 0 revenue, we were able to grow to 60% of pre-pandemic monthly revenue.)
- Helped evolve selection, evaluation and competency frameworks for Income Share Agreement programs (ISA) programs. This helped in choosing the right learners and handpick them for jobs. This enabled us to go into Tier 3 cities and enable freshers to get ~6-7 LPA packages.
- Designed and deployed self-paced courses that are consumed by around 50,000+ learners. Helped acquire learners and deliver our programs internationally (in Canada).
- Helped setup the basic analytics dashboard for tracking learner outcomes.
- Evolved the product roadmap for an inhouse LMS Glabs that has ~50k users which hosts the curriculum and content. Worked closely with the tech team to prioritize features from the learner point of view along with furnishing the detailed requirements.

Indian Institute of Technology, Madras PhD Research Scholar

July 2010 - June 2018 (8 years)
(Currently paused. Not graduated yet)

I was working towards a PhD in Natural Language Processing and Memory based reasoning in Artificial Intelligence. The main focus of the research is trying to answer the question - Can we improve the efficiency of the task if we are complexity aware instead of complexity agnostic? Have published papers in International Conference in Case Based Reasoning (ICCBR) and FLAIRS based on the work.

IBM India Research Labs Research Intern May 2012 - August 2012 (4 months) Bangalore, India

Interned with the Human Language Technologies Group by working on topic modelling over speech-to-text transcripts.

## Education

Indian Institute of Technology, Madras

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) (on pause), Computer Science · (2010 - 2018)

Sri Sathya Sai Institute of Higher Learning
Master of Technology (M.Tech.), Computer Science · (2008 - 2010)

Sri Sathya Sai Institute of Higher Learning

Master of Science (MSc), Mathematics and Computer Science · (2006 - 2008)

Sri Sathya Sai Institute of Higher Learning Bachelor of Science (BSc), Mathematics · (2003 - 2006)